A Guide to the International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC) records FA084
Rockefeller Archive Center
- IBEC, 1946-1980; 8; 71.47 Cubic Feet 182 letter document boxes and 5 legal document boxes
  - HISPANIBEC, S. A. - Spain - Reports, 1966-1972 (Box 191, Folder 1135)
    Report, brochure, prospectus. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - Hybrid Poultry Farm, 1967-1973 (Box 191, Folder 1136)
    Magazine, news clipping, report, brochure. Poultry industry information. Arbor Acres. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Credit Ratings, 1965-1976 (Box 191, Folder 1137)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report. Digest of personal data on the top management of American Industry. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Directors, 1948-1976 (Box 192, Folder 1138)
    Correspondence, telex, news clipping, press release, summary, report, memorandum, agreement, telegram, article, minutes. Information about board meetings. Update folder. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Equipment and Supplies, 1946-1971 (Box 192, Folder 1139)
    Correspondence, memorandum, cablegram, news clipping, receipts. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Accounting, 1962-1968 (Box 192, Folder 1140)
    Correspondence, receipts, telex, telegram, minutes, article, memorandum, report, balance. Information relating to expense accounts. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Accounting, 1969-1976 (Box 193, Folder 1141)
    Correspondence, memorandum, summary, telex, balance, report, press release. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - New York - Finance - Bank Accounts (A-F), 1971-1976 (Box 193, Folder 1142)
    Correspondence, memorandum. Information concerning accounts in various banks. Update folder. Previous correspondence on microfiche. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - New York - Chase Manhattan Bank - Finance - Accounts, 1971-1974 (Box 193, Folder 1143)
    Correspondence, telex. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - New York - Chase Manhattan Bank - Finance - Accounts, 1973-1977 (Box 193, Folder 1144)
  - IBEC - New York - Finance - Bank Accounts (L-Z), 1957-1976 (Box 194, Folder 1145)
    Correspondence, memorandum, certificate. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - New York - Finances - Bank Safe Deposit Boxes, 1975 (Box 194, Folder 1146)
  - IBEC - New York - Capital Stock - Affiliated Companies, 1973 (Box 194, Folder 1147)
  - IBEC - Finance - Accounting - Capital Stock, 1959-1965 (Box 194, Folder 1148)
    Correspondence. Mutual requests for investment funds. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - New York - Capital, 1970-1976 (Box 194, Folder 1149)
    Correspondence, report, receipts, article, summary, brochure, journal, certificate, memorandum. Update folder. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Capital Stock - Quotations, 1967-1970 (Box 194, Folder 1150)
    Report, memorandum, news clipping, newspaper. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Capital Stock, 1962-1971 (Box 194, Folder 1151)
    Correspondence, memorandum, draft, prospectus. Requests for prospectus. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Capital Stock, 1973-1974 (Box 195, Folder 1152)
    Correspondence, report by Kuhn, Loeb and Co. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Capital Stock - Shareholders, 1962-1976 (Box 195, Folder 1153)
    Correspondence, report, notes, telegram, press release, article, certificate, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English, German and French.
  - IBEC - Capital Stock - Shareholders - United Church Board for World Ministries, 1968-1971 (Box 195, Folder 1154)
    Correspondence, memorandum, article, report, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Capital Stock - Stock Exchanges, 1970 (Box 195, Folder 1155)
    Article, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Capital Stock, 1968-1975 (Box 195, Folder 1156)
    Correspondence, report, receipts, summary, memorandum. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Debentures, 1962 (Box 196, Folder 1157)
    Report. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Devaluation of Currencies, 1966-1971 (Box 196, Folder 1158)
    Correspondence, cablegram, article, telex, bulletin, report, news clipping, memorandum. Information of devaluation in countries such as Argentina, Brazil. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Financial Statements, 1970-1975 (Box 196, Folder 1159)
    Correspondence, memorandum, press release, balance, report, news clipping, summary. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Financial Statements - Distribution, 1962-1975 (Box 196, Folder 1160)
  - IBEC - Finance - Foreign Exchange, 1962-1975 (Box 196, Folder 1161)
    Correspondence, memorandum, telex, certificate, report, cablegram, balance. Legal papers such as power of attorney. Documents in this folder are in English, Spanish and Portuguese.
  - IBEC - Finance - Guarantees, 1968-1973 (Box 196, Folder 1162)
    Memorandum, report, summary. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Incorporation, 1967-1974 (Box 197, Folder 1163)
    Memorandum, summary, report, certificate. Legal papers. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Accounting - Income - Holding Company, 1952-1957 (Box 197, Folder 1164)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, summary. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Insurance, 1966-1973 (Box 197, Folder 1165)
    Correspondence, receipts, memorandum, newsletter, report, telex, directory, article. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - New York - Finance - Inventory Management, 1967-1971 (Box 197, Folder 1166)
    Report, article, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Investments - Foreign Direct Investments, 1966-1975 (Box 197, Folder 1167)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, journal. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Investments - Divestment Inquiries, 1973-1974 (Box 197, Folder 1168)
  - IBEC - Finance - Accounting - Mutual Investment Funds, 1960-1966 (Box 197, Folder 1169)
    Correspondence, memorandum, summary, telegram, news clipping, report. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans, 1970-1976 (Box 197, Folder 1170)
    Correspondence, summary, report, memorandum, press release. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - File #1, 1971-1976 (Box 198, Folder 1171)
    Correspondence, memorandum. Confirmation letters, American Express Co. Inc. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - File #2, 1971-1975 (Box 198, Folder 1172)
    Correspondence, memorandum, telex. Confirmation letters from banks. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - File #3, 1971-1975 (Box 198, Folder 1173)
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - File #4, 1959-1976 (Box 198, Folder 1174)
    Correspondence, memorandum, agreement, summary, notes, telex. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - [IBEC - Finance], 1964-1965 (Box 198, Folder 1175)
    Brochure, report. Financial statements. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1976-1977 (Box 199, Folder 1176)
    Correspondence. Accords, notice of borrowing. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1971-1975 (Box 199, Folder 1177)
    Correspondence, agreement, memorandum, balance. Notice of borrowing, prepayment confirmation. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1959-1964 (Box 199, Folder 1178)
    Correspondence, agreement. Loan agreements. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - Chase Eurodollar Loan, 1971-1974 (Box 199, Folder 1179)
    Correspondence, agreement, memorandum. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - Government, 1959-1968 (Box 199, Folder 1180)
    Correspondence, memorandum, minutes, telegram, report, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans - Morgan Guaranty Trust Co. of New York, 1968-1974 (Box 200, Folder 1181)
    Correspondence, agreement, memorandum, report. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Purchase Offers, 1974-1976 (Box 200, Folder 1182)
  - IBEC - Finance - Short Term Paper, 1963-1971 (Box 200, Folder 1183)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, receipts, annual report. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Finance - Loans, 1965-1976 (Box 200, Folder 1184)
    Correspondence, memorandum, telex, balance, agreement. $20,000,000 notes. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Investments, 1972-1976 (Box 200, Folder 1185)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, summary, press release, certificate. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Taxes, 1961-1977 (Box 200, Folder 1186)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, press release, article, certificate. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Legal - Patents, 1970-1975 (Box 201, Folder 1187)
    Correspondence, report, bulletin, certificate, journal, memorandum. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English, French and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal - Powers of Attorney, 1970-1975 (Box 201, Folder 1188)
    Correspondence, memorandum, telex, cablegram, power of attorney. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English, Spanish and Portuguese.
  - IBEC - Legal - Qualification, 1973-1975 (Box 201, Folder 1189)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum. Update folder, previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal, 1973-1976 (Box 201, Folder 1190)
    Correspondence, telex. Update folder, previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal, 1972-1973 (Box 201, Folder 1191)
    Card. Announcements from law firms. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks, 1969-1975 (Box 201, Folder 1192)
    Correspondence, news clipping, directory, memorandum, news clipping, brochure, plans, journal, magazine, advertisement. Housing Division. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks, 1970-1975 (Box 202, Folder 1193)
    Correspondence, memorandum, article, receipts, report, telex, brochure, agreement, bulletin. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries (A), 1970-1975 (Box 202, Folder 1194)
    Correspondence, memorandum, journal, bulletin, news clipping, telex, report, agreement, power of attorney. Information about patent registration and renewal in Africa, Argentina, Australia and Austria. Previous correspondence microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries (B), 1967-1975 (Box 203, Folder 1195)
    Correspondence, receipts, bulletin, memorandum, power of attorney, newsletter, certificate. Belgium, Bangladesh, Benelux, Brazil, Bolivia. Previous correspondence on microfilm. Documents in this folder are in English and Portuguese.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries (C), 1970-1975 (Box 203, Folder 1196)
    Correspondence, journal, memorandum, bulletin, telex, power of attorney. Canada, Central America, Chile, China, Colombia, Costa Rica, Cyprus, Czechoslovakia. Previous correspondence on microfilm. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries (D-I), 1970-1975 (Box 204, Folder 1197)
    Correspondence, journal, memorandum, power of attorney, receipts, bulletin, certificate, draft, prospectus, brochure, catalogue. Guatemala, Germany, Hungary, Haiti, Hong Kong, India, Honduras, Ecuador, Dominican Republic, Denmark, FInland, France, Iran, Israel, Italy. Documents in this folder are in English, German, French and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries - Japan, 1970-1975 (Box 204, Folder 1198)
    Correspondence, memorandum, power of attorney, news clipping, telex. Previous correspondence on microfilm. Documents in this folder are in English and Japanese.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries (K-T), 1970-1975 (Box 204, Folder 1199)
    Correspondence, memorandum, draft, telegram, bulletin, news clipping. Nicaragua, New Zealand, Netherlands, Monaco, Mexico, Kuwait, Korea, Norway, Portugal, Puerto Rico, Poland, Peru, Paraguay, Panama, Pakistan, Spain, Switzerland, Sweden, Thailand, Trinidad and Tobago. Previous correspondence on microfilm. Documents in this folder are in Japanese, Portuguese and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Legal - Trademarks - Countries (U-Z), 1971-1975 (Box 205, Folder 1200)
    Correspondence, memorandum, news clipping, certificate, telex, receipts. Venezuela, Uruguay, United States, United Kingdom. Previous correspondence on microfilm. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions, 1966-1976 (Box 205, Folder 1201)
    Correspondence, memorandum, speech, newsletter, press release, telex, report, article, news clipping, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions (A-B), 1966-1976 (Box 205, Folder 1202)
    Correspondence, memorandum, telex, report, advertisement, proposal, bulletin, catalogue. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions - American Research and Development (ARD), 1969-1972 (Box 206, Folder 1203)
    Correspondence, memorandum, article, annual report, report, news clipping, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions (C-F), 1968-1975 (Box 206, Folder 1204)
    Correspondence, prospectus, memorandum, report, advertisement, draft, brochure, photograph, notes, balance, bulletin. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions (G-I), 1967-1972 (Box 207, Folder 1205)
    Correspondence, memorandum, proposal, brochure, report, catalogue, annual report, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions (J-L), 1966-1975 (Box 207, Folder 1206)
    Correspondence, report, memorandum, summary, telex, article, press release, prospectus, cablegram. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions (M-R), 1968-1976 (Box 207, Folder 1207)
    Correspondence, report, annual report, balance, memorandum, brochure, article, plans, catalogue, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions (S-Z), 1968-1972 (Box 208, Folder 1208)
    Correspondence, memorandum, brochure, news clipping, report, balance, prospectus, annual report, press release, photograph. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions - W. R. Grace and Co., 1960-1970 (Box 208, Folder 1209)
    Correspondence, balance, report, memorandum, article, news clipping. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Mergers and Acquisitions - Northrup King and Co., 1967-1971 (Box 208, Folder 1210)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, agreement, balance, prospectus, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - Dilworth, J. Richardson - Papers (Box 208, Folder 1211)
  - IBEC - Organization - Charts, 1968-1975 (Box 208, Folder 1212)
    Chart. Information about the general organization of IBEC. Update folder, previous correspondence and chart microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization, 1947-1975 (Box 209, Folder 1213)
    Memorandum, correspondence, press release, report, bulletin, notes, chart. Information regarding staff/corporate organization. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Accountability, 1972-1973 (Box 209, Folder 1214)
  - IBEC - Finance - Division Responsibilities, 1966 (Box 209, Folder 1215)
    Memorandum, report, chart. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Audit and Compensation Committee, 1973-1974 (Box 209, Folder 1216)
    Memorandum, minutes. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Corporate Regional Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 209, Folder 1217)
    Correspondence, memorandum, contract. Information about meeting schedules. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Coordinating, 1967-1973 (Box 209, Folder 1218)
    Memorandum. Information regarding IBEC Foods, Inc. and IBEC trading. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Disclosure, 1969 (Box 209, Folder 1219)
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation, 1967-1977 (Box 209, Folder 1220)
    Correspondence, memorandum, minutes, draft, article, inventory. Inventory of donations. Update folder, previous correspondence on microfilm. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (A-Al), 1966-1976 (Box 209, Folder 1221)
    Correspondence, receipts, article, report, brochure, annual report, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English, Spanish and Portuguese.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (Am), 1965-1976 (Box 209, Folder 1222)
    Correspondence, brochure, annual report, report, program, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (An-At), 1966-1976 (Box 210, Folder 1223)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, receipts, journal, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (B-C), 1966-1976 (Box 210, Folder 1224)
    Correspondence, brochure, summary, catalogue, prospectus, report, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (D-E), 1969-1976 (Box 210, Folder 1225)
    Correspondence, report, annual report, journal, brochure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (F-H), 1965-1974 (Box 210, Folder 1226)
    Correspondence, news clipping, brochure, report, memorandum, catalogue. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (I), 1962-1975 (Box 211, Folder 1227)
    Correspondence, report, prospectus, annual report, proposal, brochure, journal, newsletter, catalogue, receipts, memorandum, bulletin. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (J-M), 1965-1976 (Box 211, Folder 1228)
    Correspondence, brochure, news clipping, summary, memorandum, newsletter, annual report, press release, journal, report, photograph. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (N), 1965-1976 (Box 212, Folder 1229)
    Correspondence, memorandum, brochure, report, annual report, journal. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (O-R), 1964-1976 (Box 212, Folder 1230)
    Correspondence, report, news clipping, memorandum, summary, magazine, annual report, newsletter, advertisement. Documents in this folder are in English, Portuguese and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (S-T), 1967-1976 (Box 213, Folder 1231)
    Correspondence, brochure, news clipping, photograph, yearbook, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Donation (U-Z), 1966-1976 (Box 213, Folder 1232)
    Correspondence, brochure, news clipping, report, catalogue, summary, telex, memorandum. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - European Advisory, 1966-1976 (Box 213, Folder 1233)
    Correspondence, telex, memorandum, telegram, notes, newsletter, minutes, program. Information about meetings with the European IBEC Advisory Committee. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English, French and German [with translation].
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Executive Meetings and Minutes, 1969-1975 (Box 214, Folder 1234)
    Memorandum, summary, minutes. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Management (A-C), 1968-1972 (Box 214, Folder 1235)
    Correspondence, telex, summary, report, minutes, brochure, memorandum, notes. Information about staff, monthly operating forecast, and meetings. Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Finance, 1968-1973 (Box 214, Folder 1236)
    Report, minutes, memorandum. Microfilmed. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Foreign Direct Investments, 1968 (Box 214, Folder 1237)
    Correspondence, memorandum, newsletter. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Management (D-Z), 1967-1974 (Box 215, Folder 1238)
    Correspondence, report, minutes, memorandum, news clipping, telex. Meeting information in Venezuela, Thailand, Spain, Peru, Mexico. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Operating, 1973 (Box 215, Folder 1239)
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Operating and Coordinating, 1965-1968 (Box 215, Folder 1240)
    Correspondence, memorandum, notes, report, minutes, cablegram. Area operating reports: Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Peru, Spain. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Planning, 1964-1975 (Box 215, Folder 1241)
  - IBEC - Organization - Committees - Real Estate, 1972-1973 (Box 215, Folder 1242)
  - IBEC - Organization - Corporate Management Information, 1967-1976 (Box 216, Folder 1243)
    Report, memorandum, article. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Management - Regional, 1964-1976 (Box 216, Folder 1244)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, minutes, telegram, chart, telex. Information regarding the political, economical, financial and social situation. Argentina, Brazil, Colombia, Europe, Iran, El Salvador, Mexico, Peru, Spain, Thailand, Venezuela. Documents in this folder are in English and Spanish.
  - IBEC - Organization - Management - Regional Forecast, 1970-1973 (Box 216, Folder 1245)
    Report on different countries. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Meetings - European Managers, 1967-1968 (Box 216, Folder 1246)
  - IBEC - Organization - Office Procedure, 1971-1976 (Box 217, Folder 1247)
    Correspondence, memorandum. Information about staff procedure. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Office Procedure, 1966-1970 (Box 217, Folder 1248)
  - IBEC - Organization - Office Procedure, 1962-1965 (Box 217, Folder 1249)
    Correspondence, memorandum, report, minutes. Documents in this folder are in English.
  - IBEC - Organization - Office Procedure - Tab File, 1947-1975 (Box 218, Folder 1250)
    Correspondence, certificate, report, agreement, newsletter, memorandum, proxy. Information concerning central files and staff procedures policies. Documents in this folder are in English.